欢迎大家观看JWST天文学观测提案工具(APT)用户界面简单介绍
Welcome to a brief overview of the Astronomers Proposal Tool user interface for JWST.
本视频将提供软件界面的高级指导
This video will provide some high-level guidance about the interface,
并定义了JWST文档和其他视频教程中会用到的术语
and defined terms that will be used elsewhere in the JWST documentation and other video tutorials.
APT目前在Mac Windows Linux上平台可用
APT is currently available in Macintosh Windows and Linux versions.
外观有所区别 但功能完全相同
Primary differences being cosmetic, they all have the exact same functionality.
APT界面中最熟悉的部分是菜单栏
The most familiar component of the APT interface is the menu bar,
由标准的下拉菜单组成
which consists of your standard drop-down menus.
菜单栏位置取决于您的操作系统
The location of the menu bar is dependent upon your operating system.
下面一排大图标是顶部工具条
You know that the large row of icons is known as the top toolbar.
HST相关工具以灰色显示
HST specific tools will be grayed out.
左侧窗口为树状编辑器
The leftmost window is the tree editor,
其中单个项目称为容器
and individual items within it are referred to as containers.
容器旁边有箭头 可以点击展开更多选项
There's an arrow next to container, you can click it for more options.
右侧大窗口为活动GUI窗口
The large window to the right is the active GUI window.
活动的GUI窗口内容将根据您所选择的工具和特定的容器而改变
The contents of the active GUI window will change depending on which tool you have selected
and the particular container.
视频中我们已经开启了一个观测提案
We've started with a proposal open already.
想再开启新提案 请点击下拉菜单中的"New JWST Proposal"
To begin a new proposal, select "New JWST Proposal" from the drop-down menu.
使用树状编辑器切换您已开启的提案
Use the tree editor to move back and forth between your open proposals.
您可以按住Option或Alt键点击容器左侧箭头来展开全部子项
You can use the Option or Alt key when clicking on an arrow to reveal all it's nested containers.
回到顶部工具条 "Format Editor"与树形编辑器为APT的主要输入模式
Returning to the top toolbar, the Format Editor used in conjunction with the tree editor
is the main entry mode used with APT.
"MSA Planning Tool"为近红外光谱仪(NIRSpec)微快门总成(MSA)创建观测计划
The MSA Planning Tool is used to create plans and observations for NIRSpec Micro-Shutter Assembly.
"Visit Planner"用于验证您的观测提案在时间表上的可行性
The Visit Planner is a tool used to verify the schedule bility of your proposed observations,
并在出现任何问题时提供诊断
and will provide diagnostics in the case of any problems.
"Timeline"可以图形化显示您的观测提案的时间花销
Timeline shows a graphical representation of the overheads that are affecting your proposed observations.
"View in Aladdin"可为您提供集成版的阿拉丁可视化工具
View in Aladdin gives an integrated version of the Aladdin Visualization Tool
可以以可视化的形式辅助您的观测提案计划
to help plan and visualize your observations.
"Target Confirmation"为您的提案中的所有固定目标生成目标确认表
Target Confirmation generates target confirmation charts for all fixed targets in your proposal.
"PDF Preview"可以在提交前进行提案审查
PDF Preview gives several options to review summaries of your proposal before submission.
"Submission"用于提交(或在需要时重新提交)您的提案
Submission is where you'll submit your proposal and necessary resubmit.
最后 "Errors and Warnings"会给出您的提案中所有错误和警告的诊断报告总结
Finally, Errors and Warnings will give you a summary diagnostic report
of all the errors and warnings currently in your proposal.
除了给出错误和警告外 APT还提供上下文关联的帮助
In addition to errors and warnings, context-sensitive help is also available with APT.
界面中蓝色文字表示有上下文关联的帮助内容
Words in blue indicate context-sensitive help is available for that topic.
将鼠标指向该词 您会看到指针旁出现一个问号
If you point your mouse over the word you'll see the pointer requires a question mark,
表明上下文关联的帮助内容可用
indicating context-sensitive help is available.
点击该文本将启动浏览器并加载相应的JDox页面
Clicking the text will launch your web browser and load the appropriate JDox page,
提供关于该主题的更多帮助
giving more help on that topic.
菜单栏还有"JWST Help"选项 其中有重要网页的链接
The menu bar also has a "JWST Help" menu that has links to important web pages,
以及联系JWST服务台的方法
as well as ways of contacting the JWST Help Desk.
APT用户界面概述到此结束
This concludes the APT user interface overview.
更多详细内容请观看我们的其他视频或JDox文章
See our other videos or JDox articles for more detailed information.
如需要关于您观测提案的具体帮助 请联系JWST服务台
For help with your specific proposal, contact the JWST Help Desk.